Ken Sutton

1025 East Robinhood Drive Arlington, WA 98223 (714) 394-2964

kwsutton1966@gmail.com

Summary

25 years of ministry experience as a Pastor. Skill-set includes pastoral care, counseling, teaching, directing and budgeting. Recognized strengths include effective communication in all forms, positive interaction with both the public and parishioners and utilizing time management skills. My experience working closely with and building strong positive relationships with church leadership, the public and co-workers will help me to function well in a Hospital setting.

Experience

Pastor 1993 - Present

Calvary Chapel

- Pastored churches in England, Romania, Canada & U.S.
- Provided pastoral care which included hospital visits, counseling, officiating weddings and conducting memorial services
- Organized the Cristia Music Festival in Cluj, Romania. Attendance 3000
- Planted a bi-lingual church in the heart of Transylvania

Pastor 2016 - Present

City on a Hill Church

- Planted a new Calvary Chapel in Snohomish County in 2016
- Provides pastoral care and oversight to a congregation of 100 in Smokey Point
- Conducts regular hospital visits, provides counseling, responsible for discipleship of those attending the church

Calvary Chapel Bible College

2012 - 2015

- 3 hour weekly lectures to 30 students per semester
- Creating, writing and grading exams
- Syllabus creation

Men's Pastor 2012 – 2015

Calvary Chapel Costa Mesa

- Assumed my former duties in Costa Mesa, providing spiritual care to approximately 300 men
- Taught weekly at the Calvary Chapel School of Ministry

Senior Pastor 2008 – 2012

Calvary Chapel Everett

- Planted a Calvary Chapel in North Everett, launched September 2008
- Calvary Everett took on responsibility for the annual Calvary Chapel Romania conference. We sent multiple teams over to help facilitate the conferences in Oradea, Romania.
- Helped oversee multiple street ministries and outreach ministries in the community

Men's Pastor 2005 - 2008

Calvary Chapel Costa Mesa

- Responsible for teaching a weekly study for approximately 300 men
- Was responsible for an aid trip to Romania with 20 men
- Helped plan and implement our annual men's conferences and retreats

Regional Pastor 2001 - 2005

Canadian affiliated Calvary Chapel churches

- Provided oversight to all our Canadian churches
- Responsible for affiliating pastors in all 10 provinces
- Implemented the national ministry conference in Vancouver
- Helped church's navigate through internal conflict within there local communities
- Regularly visited Canadian churches to provide encouragement and counsel to pastors

Further employment history available upon request

Education & Certifications

- Faith International University Seminary Degree Completion, Religion Tacoma, WA June 2020
- University of Oregon Degree Prerequisites Eugene, OR 1989
- George Fox College- Degree Prerequisites 1986 Newberg, OR
- Bellevue Christian High School Diploma Bellevue, WA 1984

Volunteer History

- Led multiple teams into Eastern Europe and Mexico to construct orphanages and to provide aid to various communities
- Volunteer for a Hurricane Katrina relief team in 2013, rebuilding parts of the New Jersey shore.

Skills and Attributes

- 25 years Teaching & Public Speaking experience Local churches, conferences, college and community groups
- 7 years of Radio Hosting host of Pastor's Perspective, a daily program broadcast on 107.9 in Orange County, CA.
- 25 years of Pastoral Care Hospital visits, counseling, memorial services, crisis intervention, community service, etc.
- 25 years of budget/financial oversight Responsible for running an organization within a annual budget
- 25 years of leading local church teams Responsible for assistant staff, lay leaders, Sunday school teachers, janitors etc.
- 17 years of ordaining pastors and church planting
- Effective Communicator preparing and delivering presentations, written or electronic correspondence and documentation as well as verbal communication
- Stress Management skills Ability to function and complete tasks accurately with multiple interruptions
- Interpersonal skills which gives me the ability to create strong relationships internally and externally
- Multi-tasking Ability to work diverse issues.
- Highly effective time management skills

Professional References

Kelley Taylor – Pastor Calvary Chapel Lake Stevens (425) 335-4819 Brian Brodersen – Pastor Calvary Chapel Costa Mesa (714) 979-4422 James Siderius - Pastor City on a Hill Church (425) 308-3917